yo yo I'm back on the periscope you love
the periscope you know what I realized I
didn't emphasize enough so what you are
seeing right here so the car is driving
right now
what you are seeing here is open source
and you can build it today you can go to
our github
there is our device the common neo which
you can build there's also a company
called neo driven selling in our comedy
no I mean that's the hardware component
the software component is called open
pilot and it is free and open source
oops I think it's like it's just really
important emphasize that this is what
you're seeing here is its rim you can go
and get this today on your Acura ILX or
your Honda Civic and it'll try so it's
driving now
Oh Elaine
yeah
eight my Walker it was pretty good
got chicken sandwich and that they put
mayo on my chicken sandwich
it
so I try to find a better place to mount
it I didn't really have any ideas open
to suggestions
pilot bros
all right now I have to figure out where
I want to get off this Highway
Fairfield
it did this once where I ended up going
to Sacramento and not doing the 550 cut
across I believe it's the 550 because I
got my periscope up and off guess what
else I have fixed which I'm really
excited about so the internet for some
reason my drive px2
lost its IP address which is kind of
sketchy
I mean look like Ubuntu does a really
bad job of what's not that Ubuntu does a
bad job Ubuntu itself does a good job
but if you put things like Etsy network
interfaces network manager and that I
think like if videos got some other
thing running on this on the internet
breaks which sucks but I now have
Spotify back on my large touchscreen
which is nice and I'm very excited about
Spotify
user distracted that's right I was
distracted heaven enough
do I speak French now I don't
what do I think about French I don't
know be French yeah now we got music
price is better
Leslie sitting in a car you're that song
car radio by twenty one pilots that is
what they describe it very well when
your radio doesn't work drop an iOS
jailbreak the with like a million bucks
now
again and now I know there we go how
long am i driving three hours I got a
date tonight in Chico
y'all want to drive with me welcome
Oh traffic but we gallop the pilot makes
traffic easy it's open source if you
download her get up get up that
list is the music good quality at all
drop a freestyle yo that's a lot of time
what I do when I'm in the car by myself
I care my best to freestyle I sound
stupid sometimes I get real good
freestyle and I'm like damn I wish I
could only have good freestyle
now you get to see that yeah so Maya
this is might discover weekly it's a mix
of like emo music and rap music and all
the best we got some cars up here pay
attention
I thought it looked at Tesla's autopilot
no I don't own a Tesla I tried to buy a
Tesla and all the co more track I get
distracted too easily this periscope
um not like from driving I just mean
like from what I'm saying right half of
its kind of hard to keep a train of
thought while you're also driving a car
it's interesting you know like the whole
dynamics of
[Music]
[Applause]
I was feeling that 303 let's go back to
that so I'm running x86 Spotify on my
arm 64 in queue at meal so it's really
slow and crappy
and I think the Spotify Linux app has
some bug where if you use it with a
touchscreen it breaks
it breaks X
oh you doing yeah
what do I think about neo driven you're
driven is cool they sell Neos what I
think of Martin shkreli Martin shkreli
is banned from Twitter and that's sad
because I enjoyed following him on
Twitter
Plus cutie
oh oh that's cutie no well it's can't
just be cutie because I'll get cutie
like yeah
Spotify Linux does use cutie I believe
um but it can't just be cutie because it
actually breaks like other windows from
working so maybe that's something to do
with the interaction with no more oh no
don't you know that much about expose
but they should if someone from Spotify
is watching they should build an arm 64
yeah
[Laughter]
look yeah that's what I say the car
companies are gonna be like man I mean
like guys like better right look at
Nokia look at blackberry and the real
irony is it's going to be the high-end
car companies that like really think
they're gonna solve self-driving
themselves that really suffer from this
um because the low-end car companies are
going to be much quicker to adopt
Android and it's what we are so we are
we make this software called open pilot
open pilot is an open-source version of
test the auto pilot
it's what's driving the car that I'm in
right now and
some car companies are going to embrace
open pilot and they're gonna be like the
companies that embraced Android right
like they're gonna be the Samsungs and
even the HTC's I mean would you rather
be HTC or Nokia today like you can say
HTC is not doing great but Nokia was
written off entirely as a loss right
nokey did other things too like but
really the phone's is where they lost it
Symbian OS I had one of those in high
school um you said something
do I remind me what you said Oh 90% of
commutes by the 90% maybe it's gonna be
it's gonna be a stretch it depends on
how well our mapping stop starts coming
together so we have six minutes so
that's six minutes on open pilot if you
don't interact with the car for six
minutes it beeps and it has you take at
all all right
Vacaville in nine months
I have to turn and Chico is the Mad far
yo this is bad far
I met this girl she drove down from
Chico's San Francisco to hang out and
now I'm like mad she goes back far
you'll hear about cash anymore do you
why after six minutes it keeps the
driver engaged right you don't want you
know what people lulled into thinking
that this is a level four self-driving
car it's knowledge even if it doesn't
make mistakes that often you still need
to pay attention at all times and
because it still does make mistakes at a
higher rate than a human oh and this is
true for every single self-driving
system this is true for Google this is
true for Tesla it's true
well you need one camera to drive down
this engagement yes probably but at
least an official right I think it may
be possible to get to level four with
one really good fish eye and like
sirenix
don't pile a volte I don't know what
level key is I call it by a tip I'm a
sucker for buying things I love buying
things
consumerism is great folks it could be
less hard on the brakes there so you see
that situation where the lead so the car
to a head is at a dead stop I know that
the car in front of me isn't going to
move anytime soon so I couldn't get on
the brakes even earlier a lot of driving
smoothly in traffic has to do with
predicting what like the cars in your
lane are going to do if you knew exactly
what the car in front of you was gonna
do say like you know a couple seconds
ahead you could drive so smoothly
freeway is 90% of all driving that's
true
and and traffic like this I don't know
how people do this every day
I have no commute I live in the office I
don't know how people sit in this kind
of traffic
this chimed out AI legette no
b2b is joke if the driver doesn't take
control after six minutes the car stops
accelerating so the the cruise control
starts and stops going B to B is a joke
Peter V is a bigger joke than drive that
AI a 16 G is cool
we like a 16z juice
expand zooks zoosk no no so like on a
scale of legitness
there's probably drive that AI is the
most legit out of Zuke's v2v and drive
that AI Zuke's is the least legit it's
not even the dukes doesn't have good
people or good tech it's just that
they're never gonna succeed like what
they're aiming for is this like
everyone's gonna be riding around in a
zukes Baz and like I just don't know
like you're not gonna you're I mean okay
fine your valuations like 2 billion
dollars but like if you really are gonna
revolutionize all these different parts
and yeah that's what they're reinventing
everything um have I met metallic of
course I've ever challenged yeah yeah
zooks you you can't reinvent everything
Oh economy our goal is to own a very
small part of the driving horizontal we
want to basically replace the driver
with software and that's it we don't
want to build cars we don't own fleets
we don't own matching networks we want
to work with people for that well I did
get a big payday
why chaser wait for the last 1% yeah so
please sell the 90 percent for the
freeway I mean we do better than sell it
we give it away right so what you see
right now which is just it's been
driving the car right like I'm paying
attention but it's driving I'm not doing
anything
so yeah why salad it's even better you
we don't sell it we give it away it is
on our github for free the thing that
actually drives the car um what do I
think
uber joining Auto driving Rover is
hungry I do admire ubers hunger by the
way if you're you know if you you look
at the neo and you're like this is too
hard to build you can buy one from a
company called neo driven and then
installing our software is super easy
open-source it's not exactly what you
see right here so this is open pilot 0.3
plans to come to Vegas soon baby what do
I think about way mo vs. I just want to
see the technology built you see this
guy next to me needs open pilot he's
weaving his lane six minutes if you want
I can show you what happens if you look
for six minutes or not so we got a cut
in up here
Thomas which bags you guys came over
[Music]
pleading the fifth in the civil case
doesn't look good
I should know I should know I was
involved in a civil case five years ago
yes your lawyers tell you whatever you
do don't plead the fifth who's gonna win
Noel we'll see how much effort people
put in if the bar is where it was last
year we will win we didn't put that much
effort into it our cars not really a
race car our cars not really like am i
following robot it's a highway Cruiser
because 90% of driving is done on
freeways and I'm sure far less than I'm
sure 0.01% of driving is done race
training so I threw something together
for the racetrack Andy and I were
testing in the mall parking lot a couple
nights ago it was pretty fun it's better
than was last year
is it fun to watch the event this
weekend as a spectator I think yeah I
mean look it's really interested in this
stuff all the absolute best people in
the space are there you know it's it's
sad that the automakers don't show up
this is this is the homebrew Computer
Club of self-driving cars right now
homebrew Computer Club Apple one know
your history yeah yeah well the way
budget allegedly you got to put
allegedly in their news on Subarus not
people where I think it's been mentioned
late on it lay lay lay he really didn't
have much room man me we saw the like
can't your maialex
with accurate watch to level two without
an e oh oh I mean how about this you go
try your Acura ILX and you see if you
can drive six minutes without touching
anything I'm gonna guess that you can go
15 seconds so stress is like think about
the difference between every other
manufacturer and test all the really
thing it's not like you know go buy the
Acura if you're happy with that system
keep it I thought it was crap I put in a
new system it's called open pilot it's
free and open source runs our comedy O's
comment I can hop back home / comment I
check out our github also link for our
website comment by the way we were doing
down AI before it was cool not really
before Minich you come back head like
API dot I way back in the day but now
check out vector dot vector dot AI is
common AI clone
we can get this to exposure
beautiful driving up there
what other self-driving races really do
races it's kind of more of a tech demo
the big thing we're going to be showing
off is that we got our torque limit
really upped so we have we can put a lot
of torque in the steering wheel now with
certain modifications
yeah we don't race
now music is a wireless signal area
[Music]
what music she was down I'm bored in
this theory has actually borders noodly
as soon as I put it on like that that
what so
now as possible oh gee LOI
what's the issue would give the wheel to
move with proper force well it's it's a
safety issue
right um if you're increasing the torque
limit like right now my hands are not on
the wheel right but I'm watching the
road right and the reason I feel okay
doing this is because the torque limit
on the steering wheel is really really
low even if this thing decided to
completely jerk the steering wheel yes
which is someone waiting
no problem would chance the rapper I
don't know if I heard this in oh I can't
find my phone
[Music]
you
he's now plugged in and we're about to
get to that six-minute limit again oh
but I was doing really well today
some combination of the new model
temperature not being too hot
CPU head room open palette 0.3 also has
some like we refactored controls into
controls d and planner d
thing along with like latency in systems
to be which is really exciting I mean of
course if you haven't you know you are
going to get all of these improvements
as soon as three ships yeah so we're
about to get to that six minute limit
again
six minutes
touch the wheel limit and we are going
again oh here we go north 505
how does Kali and I've cleared to make
money
well yeah I can show you the neo in a
second once I feel good doing that um I
gotta do some changes now I gotta get on
this exit here that's common I plan to
make money the joke is that once you
have a fully self-driving car we are
going to get Taco Bell to pay us money
to like say you into a destination is
like your grandmother's house right and
you want to go to your grandmother's
house but because Taco Bell yeah will
deliver people to talk about alright
well we'll drop them off and take you
right through the Taco Bell drive-thru
and then like you'll just look stupid if
you're going to the Taco Bell drive-thru
woman and you just kind of like
this kind of looks stupid if you go to
the Taco Bell no I'm not gonna order
anything my cartoon hey hang on he
pauses no way
so yeah we can get here
okay there is the deal
let me put my speed up here 265 oh it's
70 here alright go fast obviously those
solid green ley lines the variance is
real tight these lanes this road is well
marked I'm so pretty good here obviously
any concept like SEO optimization for
what what I do with SEO optimization
I'll show you guys the do you can see
now that it's like detecting a car in
front
there's a chance it'll go for this
accent let's say a little bit a little
bit of waiver sometime it goes for the
exits when they're like really well
marked like that we're gonna fix that
with some magic the moving rectangle
surrounding lay markers that's the
calibration and that's where the neural
network is looking right now biggest
problems with lane markers too many
markers are pretty child
we're also using the drive px2 to
connect to the lidar so we have an
expensive sensors on this car as well
but they're not being used to drive the
car they're just being used for
assistance of ground truthing right if
you want a really nicely calibrated
camera is lighter
why does the current take you to talk
about one instead of Taco Bell so well
maybe we can have an auction like Google
where we auction what talking about you
like whichever talking about bids more I
[Laughter]
mean like it's got like watching driving
bro it's kind of relaxing talking about
I love yo I just got a whopper and the
whopper was good but I also got a
chicken sandwich and I said no mayo they
put me I want him I really hate now
that's too bad there's like a chicken
sandwich with one bite of it
there's a chicken sandwich with one bite
of it in this bag all right let's see if
we go for this exit here and now I'm
going for the exit a little okay I touch
the steering wheel a little bit there
yeah if you're driving in the right lane
and likes to go for the exits Tom so
that was our first sort of disengagement
it was a very casual disengagement you
know it's kind of like one of those
disengagement that there's no way it's
actually gonna cause a problem if you
hadn't intervened but you know just
always Safety's number one oh okay cool
so let's change lanes here
I'm gonna not disengage the system I'm
gonna focus off with this lane I'm gonna
put the speed limit let's go
self-driving car videos so I used to
stream on Twitch I used to use the live
stream hacking on twitch and I think the
live shipping hacking on Tibet is twitch
twitch is closed hacking but I don't
think they'd be cool the self-driving
cars of Sonic game
ironically I know Kyle boat was involved
with justin.tv right founder of ruse by
the way but the spectrum of legitness
crews is above try the DI b2b ends oops
I'm open pilot and I'm phobias in Japan
they didn't left to Japan don't
anyone
doing
left-hand driving fundamentals we filter
it out in the training
the truth is things like highways that
would probably do okay but how do we
handle mark with directions with just
neural nets so we're not the integrated
with directions just yet think like
Tesla pilot right we're just go take the
most probable around um very soon we
won't be integrating with directions we
have some internal demos of this stuff
128 people in here for me maybe maybe
people are hoping for the crash why
don't people watch car you know this
thing's incredibly safe
yeah then think about the safety of this
device is it as safe as you make it as
long as you are paying attention and
ready to take over at any time it's
never going to like jerk the steering
and that's that's a guarantee
so yeah I mean it's the safe as you're
making compete with uber I missed what
you said before I have no interest in
competing with over think about uber is
they lose money like who loses a lot of
money
my next demo video Taco Bell bus -
freeze - do I love tacos tacos all times
big tackle small tacos huge tacos tall
tacos this freestyle oh it's completely
on I will tell you every time I interact
I almost never interact you
sample I'll show my hands for a bit all
right fine
don't focus my camera
yes I tell you every time I disengage so
let's see we've had a bunch of the
six-minute limits and you hear the beat
but if I disengage you'll hear a beat
pause bidets we got fire Smith days
you'll hear a beep if I disengage and
the beep is definitely all over video no
fools who really is driving let's see we
had one disengagement due to an exit and
one disengagement due to a motorcycle
we had a very near disengagement due to
a late cut in but it wasn't actually
does engagement at this age I have like
a like internal thing about them they
know like how long I have you know and I
make sure that I always have at least a
second my reaction times wait a second
civic or Acura I am in the Civic hi
sorry I'm in the Acura the Acura ILX
yes we be cruising
I mean this is this is easy driving
practices the stop-and-go stuff before
was a lot more complicated than this
we are just cruising on a straight well
marked highway this is this is the kind
of stuff over violet lettuce floor we're
in the left lane
we go in 70 there's this little final
display
by the way I opened pilot I didn't
emphasize it enough on the last stream
open pilot is free and open source you
can go to our github and you can
download it today there's a couple zone
Mike took my hands on his time
stretching it on the wheel I'm gonna
switch back to the other one
hands up you're nervous I've never had a
hand up you're under arrest
I was arrested once but I've never had
it hands up
but I think the way my lawsuit
yeah I don't know I just find anything
sad that impedes the progress of the
technology I think that there's two very
separate claims that people has made I'm
clean one is that Anthony Levin douse
key still documents if this claim is
true that's not cool
don't don't still don't you you you have
a trust relationship with your employer
don't do you think two is about patents
I have a very negative opinion on
patents so one if it's true
I hope justice is served thing to Google
don't sue people based on patents just
win suing people patents as losers but
google google also has built up a bottom
up a lot of goodwill in my book Google
doesn't necessary Google doesn't bring
frivolous lawsuits right if this were
Oracle right away I'd be like get out
get out stop suing people come on Larry
else and don't you have enough yachts
but yeah
how does it compare to Tesla autopilot
v2 oh it's better I'd say it's better
than feature I'm not quite as good as v1
as much as I rip on them oh it's not
that bad
there's much worse out there and why
Emily's new stuff is actually pretty
good talk by my wife my position is
softening on their own that's six dance
I just had to show the car every her so
I touched the story
tell you that the interests of
transparency
[Music]
what am I get up to it I'm taking a
break from calming
oh my god dates I like dates
what else do I do
pretty girl never papers play with other
stuff
there's my touchscreen thing record logs
what do you mean by logs I can show you
the touch screen right now I'm using it
to record the lidar let's talk on a
lighter
there's my touch the Neo record logs
yeah this whole trip is being lowered
right now
and then it's going to be uploaded it's
actually being uploaded as we speak but
to the cloud oh if you want to work it
coming I try absolutely we are hiring go
to comment on AI you can see both our
open positions page and the sort of
people we look for the bars very high uh
you know we're not we're not a big
company where it we're small enterprise
and everyone who works here is super
talented like the level of talent trust
me I have interviewed people who work in
some of the other self-driving car
startups the level of talent here is
unreal
so what are the skills you need in
general here's how our interview process
works after you get past our phone
screen our operations department does
phone screens and then you sit down with
me and you manage to not say anything
stupid for now I'll ask you questions
about a lot of different stuff basic
understanding what's the headcount of
that's the one secret that is the one
secret we don't talk about if we are
yeah
oh yeah so I saw things to like learn
we really value at common a I use ship
ability right so what I look for in
people is people who shipped awesome
stuff people with won competitions
Network papers and ideas that I like
[Music]
Facebook just came out with that pretty
a pretty nice video segmentation thing
looked absolutely massive apart to Train
yeah we could do it how do you redeem
comments well your income points and
cowboys are great um so we are giving
out our first ever we about some swag
too early , point holders but we're
giving out our first we're doing our
first ever big column point swag
giveaway we're giving away the first
comma pandas if you want to be one of
the first people in the world with a
comma panda course of course
we have to say at least at least within
the consumer electronics round the most
advanced car interface on the market um
you'll be able to get things you feel
your car has a plethora of sensors that
you'll be able to access to with a panda
so how do you redeem comma points you
burn them
you do well and we give you awesome
stuff also every comma point makes our
self-driving car a bit better so you
give us the data and we give back well
open violets which wouldn't be nearly as
good as it was if learned for the
contributions of all our users so um
thank you users especially a special
shout out to old dirty old dirty
um on the common point leader board he
has a common neo in a Honda Civic now
he's been getting us so much high
quality training data that we've been
using and that's part of the reason
public pilot 0.3 is cruising right now
hey check it out I got a thing
this is this is just this is just
cruising you guys like you have no idea
it feels it feels so safe right now to
like it's just you know I'm just I'm
just I'm just roost on the highway it's
doing a better job to anything I could
eight-pack region I don't know where
that is
after raising VC money and being in
charge of people of course I still have
time to hack in this is
I'm very much involved with with with
the day-to-day you said we hire great
people they mostly manage themselves oh
yeah sure I mean it'll work anyway right
the video doesn't discriminate based on
location it's not like we don't use maps
right um
I use them of course
Panda is good for what
I think I just had somebody no passed me
in a 63 AMG any chance for the public to
invest in common AI now at this time
we're a privately trading company Oh
what is the Panna do to the band is
gonna get you access to all the sensors
on your car the panel is going to get
you access to all for your real speeds
your steering angle very precise speed
measurements your odometer all that
stuff so it's kind of like a cloud
dashboard for your car that you can view
in the past also
it's if you have an electric car like
you're looking Nissan Leaf you can feel
how much each cell of your battery how
much power it has but what would I do
with that access I mean it's just look
at this as every one of these ODB Dom
goals in Tour de Nesle just made a way
to fast I was
I think we're about to hit six minutes
again okay here's the choke like we put
those videos out there's disengagement
to the videos like we reflect that's
what's real like this is this is
absolutely unstaged and on fake we are
cruising in a you're down six let's
touch of the wheel we're good
let's get back I'm gonna pass me in the
right lane I'm gon fast go fast the
speed limit
yeah we like to we like to cruise
responsibly wave them over
Emacs
who knows who knows why people make
decisions like that
I started using famine early on kept
ducek them
it just seems lighter way I like it like
actually oh you have problems at screen
I use screen as well
hi I actually the meal uses tee box
the feds still on my ass no not at all
not at all
look a lot of that was fake news we did
get a letter from Mitch we chose not to
sell the product but the truth is I'm
not sure product like that works at like
a scale of 1000 so we just decided to
open source instead and we're slowly
building out of network and hopefully by
the end of April
at the end of next month we will have
the second largest network of
self-driving cars after Tesla
yeah the disengages so I'm in the right
lane again let's switch back I'll show
you
yeah yeah well I'm gonna go fast I'm not
quite going 85 but off ever since the
afro Dawkins
you Ponton so you have the exits you
have to pay attention pretty much it I
like it every exit it might it's
probably going to want to take this exit
yeah yep say you want to take the exit
there that's gonna be fixed probably not
in 0.3 but soon after that it's really
not very annoying and like it's not like
you never what's the difference anymore
it takes I've injected on the road
because the car because the car in front
of me took the accent it decided to take
the exit as well
yeah disengagement suta exits or one of
the big sources of disengagement still
in the highlight well thinks there's an
advance
pretty much
test a lot about the old one have the
same problem they largely texting with
their feet running will think some
Beverly nodding in the same way
yeah I know Ubuntu is useful out of the
box read I'm not
who is the best chance of winning well
my money's on Tesla
my money's on Tesla waiting plug take a
look no leg locks no lame lines oh here
we go
there's a disengage we lost the ley
lines for a sec on that bridge
they've moved baby maybe a foot too far
to the right more than I liked again
that's one of those disengagement swear
nothing bad would have happened if I'd
let it go just for safety and just to
really drive I dedicated with you men
I'm also every time you do a minor
disengagement like that you train the
system so that was a disengage right
there you can see it you can see it
people I did it no I'm not sure I'm a
Krishna
hold on too long what I know I'm a
German kind of the sister
I'm absolution progress okay so there's
a way we can solve the Ling lines and
there's a way we can solve
okay so Maps localization progress very
good very good we made we made great
progress this year and finally starting
to do it let me see if we have an exit
coming up
Lipscomb for that exit
what can you do without landlines it can
do better it can do better without my
funds
what we need is kind of more of a
looking at distance
and what we also need is a bigger box if
you saw that box on open pilots now
there should be a law that's all grown
three blank lines humans can drive find
it out Lane lines will be able to drive
find out lately a lot of times we do
okay without lane lines just in that
case kappa p.m. a disengage
minor disengages like that do a great
job to train the system yeah a couple
great hires we hired a phenomenal app
developer Andy the following on Twitter
and eh - he's been responsible for the
big improvements to the iOS schiffer app
and it's mentioned on our forms which if
you haven't signed up beta that come
without a I yeah what we'll fix the lame
I think beta comma dot AI we announced
the Android beta okay this guy's going
slow gonna check Planes here's my hands
up appeal to a switch
and all pilot is going to do an armored
tank
yeah there's always going to be areas
with no ley lines and these system right
now relies on my lines been too much we
just have to kind of chase
just a little bit how do you feel with
snow snow on the road or snow after the
snow off the road doesn't matter
obviously snow on the road you should be
driving for now I'm just like you would
use cruise control of snow you shouldn't
use something like a pilot when in it
when there's snow on the road
obviously if there's piles of snow on
the side of the road the car goes fine
it's not looking to tener
upcoming milestones
[Music]
Oh pilot 0.3 in probably we have
significant improvements for the people
who have zero point two point nine
thought other automakers compared
Tesla's the only one that's even close
Tesla might even be better if you have a
v1 Tesla it's probably better don't
pilot if you have the two tests thought
I'd say open pilots better and then of
course if you have a Honda Mercedes
afford those they're such jokes
yeah I mean lots of things can cause a
disengage and the type is kind of an
ambiguity
maybe these disengages they're not very
harsh or nuts they're mostly light as
long as you're paying attention you'll
be new tech advancements surprised me
really lately
my son surprised by go
probably uncle that the biggest like net
fail to detect
things have been generally following
[Music]
yeah comedy is absolutely fine in the
rain we drive very conservatively with
distance regard front we hate tailgating
myself driving car dead about down to
dinner from the edge cases interested in
gathering the statistical normal let's
open her back to the right lane here so
I watch what
right so I put the blinker up and now I
nudged the wheel a tiny bit and then I
could let it go and it pulls me right
back into the lane
automatically change is really easy if
you have a good wine spot to tender
right so I am the blind spot detector we
thought about implementing a feature
where you could like press the button
that would do the lane change right away
but um obviously you'd be responsible
for checking your going spot so we chose
not to do that if your car has a side
radar you can access it adding Lane
changing is near trivial how can you
contribute memory safe language is more
than one camera okay how do you
contribute simplest way to contribute go
to get shiver calm or shiver common area
shiver think chauffer with no vowels
it's a tiny chauffeur Shepherd shippers
are dash cam app you can mount this on
your windshield when you're driving you
can earn comma points and you can
contribute to our data set to help train
self-driving cars um if you want to go
beyond that get your hands on a panda
connect the Panda to your car it makes
the training data more valuable and it
makes the data more valuable to you as
well and if you really want to go all
out get a supported car and get an eel
and if you have the technical ability
get an unsupported car get an EO into a
port
but what's my opinion on memory safe
languages exit coming up go for this
exit at all okay fairness engage their
identities cool I like Udacity
we've got a stopped car up ahead so I'm
just gonna change lanes as a courtesy -
my hands are on the wheel
now I'm gonna pull us back so unlike a
lot of other systems our system doesn't
disengage when you use the steering
wheel it's kind of like a Lane Keeping
Assist system early is a Lane Keeping
Assist I was the poor boy oh my camera
I'll get there
don't let me forget we don't disengage
when you touch the wheel but we do
disengage when you hit the gas and I'm
surprised more systems don't if cars are
breaking when you don't want them to the
natural human response is to hit the gas
so we disengage on gas
we don't disengage on steering so I
didn't we still call it like a disengage
from a like when we track this stuff in
the back end but it's not like I
actually like disengage the system it
kept doing the gas in the brake
more than one camera this guy's going
slow hang on just change lanes here
yeah most of hard loggin so first off
let me into the monitor so we're gonna
roll out before you see more than what
camera is we're gonna roll out a fisheye
lens for an existing smart - lot of
times when you want from our cameras is
just look scared scared
a lot of times will you walk from
multiple cameras yes
just Tom or view with the road
and efficient I will get you there
using a single camera is a kind of
guaranteed synchronization right if you
have multiple cameras you got to deal
with synchronizing them you can do it
calibrating it with respect to each
other things are just now since all
right here we go for a French here move
I'm lowering the speed manually but
Oakland pilots gonna take this turn this
is all open fire I'm sorry Lord the
speed I lowered the cruise control speed
down to 55 to take this turn it won't
accelerate on turns but I was going
faster than I'd like to say on the video
so you know this is gonna be tricky
let's see if we can do this all right
take a look what's coming up no liner is
not critical that his fake news put out
by the lidar people I'm actually putting
the speed up here I just let the speed
back up to 69 and if this was all done
by open-plan to do is press the cruise
control buttons I'm gonna do the lane
change to the left right now
no letters joke is enter coming back
you'll have to ask yeah yeah so it's a
function of speed as well if you ever
have like it
this car has a slightly up stork from
stop see this one can do a lot better
yes my camera we're mostly interested in
a fisheye and side radars and I think we
can provide a lot of autonomous
functionalities and multiple cameras
right now
might just be a it again use some edge
cases but a lot of your cases to be just
outright careful what button supported
car models so some of the Honda is like
the Honda CRV is probably the easiest
one to war to 2016 CRV has the same
connector as the Civic the 2017 CRV
has a different connector but it still
has the stuff you're gonna need on it
I'm sorry I would say that's easiest
corn has a slightly different steering
interface uses Kaline but kayla is the
same thing as Linda and protip pandas
pequin be able that loves be following
cars that don't have it so this car
Acura ILX 2016 does not have low speed
and open pilot does Lois be follow but
we're actually using a piece of hardware
to do this that we haven't released the
plans for yet so publicly that's kind of
hard I'm going for the exit
disengage I let it go it went maybe a
foot to the right saw the exit was like
that just kidding
which model years above corn so any of
corn if your car has a CC and okay ass
it's gonna be a whole lot easier
insurance I don't even know what RM is
insurance is boring
I mean I'm happy to like work with
insurance companies I do believe systems
like this make driving safer maybe like
insurance companies policy just counts
that kind of stuff I'm happy to work
with them but I don't find the industry
particularly falling now we're going for
this exit
he's seen the Accords IKEA it's it's
it's fine on the highway you'll test of
any ecstasy system I'm gonna do a lane
change the life because in this trunk
okay the real test of any ACC system is
its stop and go traffic the Accord can't
do stopping traffic the brakes can work
all the way down to zero the gas it'll
does not and that's where you're going
to need some hardware to replace so we
built we go the pedal interceptor we
built something that just like instantly
what's a my ram
besides thinking of these things
howdy why do I keep speed tailgating why
don't you speak
oh my cruise control 775 all right so
pretty happy
[Music]
some behind me once my fastest of the
changelings
let go back howdy uh yeah they probably
do berries if you have an LD but yeah
I'm over Campbell only the Senate can do
that if you get an Audi with these
features I'm sure you could like pull
out their crappy stock camera and
replace it with ours are throttled by
wire but their throttle by cam so this
is done by connecting physical
potentiometers directly to the air and
the loan has called a PCM the powertrain
control module
so yeah you can't control that over
cannon even though buddy's by wire now
it is by wire so if you want to build
something with a bunch of
analog-to-digital and digital-to-analog
converters to intercept the panel then
you can turn these cars into working
always be following chance that's what
we did we haven't released the plans for
that because safety it's like
particularly unsafe but for everything
else
no exit it didn't go for it a little
later all mister
we didn't ship it for questions of
safety not that we feel it's unsafe it's
just that we feel that we're like kind
of violent we're not using the same API
the other system is using so we're kind
of like violating that assumption for
you we don't want to do that until you
know we're sure you know myself it's
just it doesn't mess up like everyone
knows what to do if you're ever if
you're ever in a car with uncontrolled
acceleration hit the brakes I first try
neutral on neutrals not guaranteed to
work because neutral goes and a lot of
the same PCM stuff but the brakes will
always be able to overpower the gas on
the color
and if you're experimenting with any
sort of this stuff what we do is we put
pieces attainable on the other fuses and
I can pull the the fuel pump fuse out
it's going to stop
you've never had to use it
how many plays a comment that's the one
secret of coming
this guy's going real slow I'm gonna
drive
a camcorder time
how long for not a task feature so what
will you call it on Instagram the thing
about not a task features is unclear how
they're regulated so right now all open
pilot really is just like Tesla Obama is
an adaptive cruise control and Lane
Keeping Assist I think we could consider
things like stop signs and red lines to
be part of an adaptive cruise control as
well
chuckling really beyond that not quite
I'm not only yeah that that's that's
contingent on stuff where my driving am
driving up to self racing cars well I'm
actually driving to a date tonight chica
so I'm going Chico California and every
Chico
honey people have watched all our
industries
just look at not a TAS to Texas I mean
because
oh the traditional automakers this is a
joke it's an absolute joke especially
with their appropriate their approach is
very similar to Google's approach and if
Google in 10 years hasn't been able to
solve it I have no idea
not about their children they're really
I'm also just politically
I see Miss Morgan organizations where
it's impossible to do anything
I did not see that playing a big role in
the future
I'd say in the lead right now is Tesla
followed up by Weibo
oh boy I used to see Cooper but hey I
know occasionally it's not automatic
if my grandma damn I would put I would
put 10,000 on those things on the road
tomorrow I would get him made I would
never have built my own car so stupid I
would have bought some car that I liked
I want to put 10,000 of them on the road
like take a pastor's would have put him
on the road Matthew and I want to start
shuttling passengers right then uh busy
still safety driver me driver's seat but
Charlotte passengers then you're getting
old is disengagement in a day you're
getting some revenue back from the
passengers you're building up a network
like that's what I would have done
handyman want to get into many ideas but
that's not the original intention
nvidia is cool big fan big fan of a
video full disclosure I do own nvidia
stock and it made me a lot of money
monster
I also shorted mobile I and I lost money
I like I like to show his new
presentation to it seems like they're
talking about a lot more than like
wrapping the land of those chips Fifi is
dumb as okay let me tell you you
want me to beat up the Samba on the road
and I'll prepared dodged it a little bit
that's pretty cool
the baby's done you want me to be I have
a camera and you have brake lights and I
will look at your brake lights and I
would decide if you for breaking and
that's maybe a PD with radios makes no
sense
I'm headed off the pilot differ from
video solution so in video just has a
net for steering I believe now 5g
doesn't create new possibilities b2b is
Dom at a you guys say yes much
btv stop this it really is it
really is um how do we differ from
appeal Nvidia doesn't have what we have
right I had to correct them I had to
correct for that exit I just do it
almost second nature
oh we got a big turn
ends up liquor all costume
Oh II turn
there's a spot where you pulled it right
this is designated see now I wish I
could text her back really easy tell her
watch me on periscope
you know it's my date tonight